Doctor Who 1963 S05E04
神秘博士(老版) 第五季第四集
The Enemy of the World
(Whopix fan edit)
世界公敌
(粉丝剪辑版)
(Sincro: bamanzi)
(时间轴/翻译: 巴蛮子sz)
(注意: 本字幕不针对原版视频, 而是粉丝剪辑版本
https://whoflix.wordpress.com/2014/11/28/the-enemy-of-the-world/ )
Oh, there's nothing like a dip to freshen you up.
噢, 没有什么比浸泡一下更能令人神清气爽了
Hey, that's a funny looking boat.
嘿, 那艘小船样子可真有意思
It's not a boat, it's a hovercraft.
那不是小船, 那是一艘气垫船
Eh?
嗯?
You're right, it is him.
你是对的, 就是他
What are we going to do?
我们要怎么做?
A terrifying thing. It's like a sea monster.
太可怕了, 就像一个海妖一样
Oh, we'll soon get a closer look, it's coming nearer.
哦, 很快我们就可以看清楚了, 它越来越近了
Oh yes. Yes.
哦, 对了, 对
I don't think I like the look of this. Let's go.
我觉得我不喜欢这事的样子, 走吧
- Why, what's the matter?  - Come on, run!
- 为啥, 什么情况?  - 快点, 跑!
- Yeah, but...  - Don't argue, run.
- 好吧, 但是...  - 别说了, 跑
Over here!
这边来!
Hurry!
快啊!
Incredible.
不可思议
Absolutely incredible.
绝对不可思议
I'm not a specimen in a glass bowl, you know?
我可不是玻璃缸里面的标本, 知道吗?
Ah, I'm sorry. Do sit down.
啊, 抱歉. 请坐下
Oh, thank you.
噢, 谢谢你
It's just so astonishing. You are Salamander.
这太令人震惊了, 你是 Salamander
Do you see what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗?
But surely you know how alike you are?
但你肯定知道你长得多像吧?
After all, Salamander is a world figure.
毕竟来说, Salamander 是个世界级人物
Well... well my friends and I, we..
哦...我的朋友们和我, 我们
we've been out of touch...
with civilisation for a while.
我们跟文明世界有段时间没有联系了
We're visitors, so to speak, um.
On ice shall we say.
我们是游客, 应该说, 唔, 应该说是与世隔绝了(?)
I see. Where shall I start?
我明白了. 我应该从哪里开始呢?
At the beginning please.
We've been subjected to a number of attacks
请从一开始讲起. 我们已经遭受了一系列的攻击了
because I look like this Salamander of yours.
仅仅因为我看起来像你们的这个 Salamander
I'm not surprised. I'll show you why.
我不感到奇怪, 我会让你看看为什么
I have a video wire of Salamander,
我这里有段 Salamander 的视频
addressing the United Zones Conference on World Food.
他在联合区域大会的世界粮食专题的讲话
And meanwhile, over at the United Zones General Assembly,
from all over the world delegates are flocking in,
与此同时, 在联合区域大会上, 代表们从世界各地涌来
eager to hear the latest report from Leader Salamander.
都急切地想听到 Salamander 组长的最新报告
The progress, Mr President, of the Sun Conservation
establishment at Kanowa, in the Australasian Zone is...
总统先生, 对于建立在澳洲区 Kanowa 的日光保留区的进展 ...
...I'm delighted to report highly satisfactory.
...我很高兴地报告给大家：高度满意
But we cannot yet guarantee good summer holidays for all.
但我们无法保障所有地方都有漂亮的夏日
However, we have now in orbit the Mark VII Sun Catcher...
然而, 现在我们的轨道上也有了日光采集器７号
and already we have been able to
concentrate the sun's rays into much needed areas.
而且我们也已经能够将太阳射线聚焦到更有需要的区域
The great Canadian wheat plains are safe.
泛加拿大片区的小麦植物很安全
And now, Mr President: Ukraine - the grain field of the planet -
现在, 总统先生, 乌克兰 - 这个星球最主要的谷物种植地
an unfortunate area between Bucava and Kirovograd
介于 Bucava 和 Kirovograd 之间的一片不幸区域
devastated by the elements two short years ago.
两年前被自然灾害严重破坏
What have I got to say to you about that?
对此我有什么可以跟你说的呢?
I can tell you that on both banks of the Dnieper river
the corn is ripening in the sun!
我可以告诉你在第聂伯河的两岸, 玉米正在阳光下成熟!
And ten-thousand robot harvesters are moving down
to gather in fifty million tons of flour!
一万台机械收割机已经出发, 去收割五千万顿面粉!
There's nothing there to say he's a bad man.
真没法说他是一个坏人
I quite agree, Victoria.
He seems to be a public benefactor.
我相当赞成, Victoria. 他似乎是一个为大众利益着想的人
Quite a speaker too and remarkably handsome,
didn't you think so Jamie?
相当会说话, 也极其有魅力. 你不觉得吗, Jamie?
He's one of the most popular men on the planet.
他是这个星球上最受欢迎的人之一
Many people call him the shopkeeper of the world.
很多人称呼他为这个世界的掌柜(?)
The saviour, in fact, some of them.
救世主, 事实上有些人这样称呼他
Well what's he saved the world from?
哦, 他把这个世界从什么手里救了?
Starvation - too many people, too little food.
饥荒 - 人太多, 食物太少
Until Salamander invented his Sun Store.
Surely you've heard? You must know?
直到 Salamander 发明了日光储存器. 你肯定听说过吧?
Oh yes, well of course we've heard something.
噢, 是的, 当然了我们听说了一点
The Sun Store collects the rays from the sun
and stores them in concentrated form.
日光存储器采集太阳射线, 集中存储起来
Oh, like the ioniser, Doctor?
喔, 就像离子器吧, 博士?
Yes, a rather different principle I think, Jamie.
是的, 但原理上很不一样, 据我了解, Jamie
Well never mind how it works! What's it for?
得了别管它什么原理了! 它是用来干什么的?
Salamander can force-grow three,
sometimes four, crops in one summer.
Salamander 可以强制让作物在一个夏天就长三茬, 甚至四茬
Well why do these men want to kill him.
那为什么这些人还想杀他
I mean, one minute you say he's saving the world, the next...
我是说, 前一分钟你说他拯救了世界, 下一分钟...
For his own ends! Step by step
he's taking control of this planet.
他有他自己的目的! 一步一步地, 他掌握了这个星球的控制权
You have proof of this?
你说这个有证据吗?
Some, yes. I was once a high official
in the World Zone Authority
是的, 有一些. 我一度也是世界区域总部的一名高官
Deputy Security Leader for North Africa and Europe,
but Salamander discredited and ruined me
是北非和欧洲的安全副主管. 但 Salamander 抹黑了我, 让我下台
because he realized I was beginning to get suspicious.
因为他发现我开始起疑了
But you could be making up stories about Salamander!
Out of revenge.
但你可能是在编造 Salamander 的故事, 出于报复!
Yes, I suppose so. Then you can judge for yourself.
是的, 我也会这么想. 你可以自己判断
You remember Michael Assevski -
he was Controller of the Eastern European Zone?
你记得 Michael Assevski 吗? 曾经的西欧区控制员?
He was drowned at sea a mile from shore.
(s/Shockingly/Hockingham,/) murdered!
他在离海岸一英里的地方淹死了. 可怕的谋杀啊!
All of them were seen with Salamander,
or a man known as his deputy
所有这些人都被见到跟 Salamander 在一起, 或者他的副官
shortly before their deaths.
都是在他们死前不久
All of them were replaced by men
known to be in Salamander's power.
据了解, 所有这些人都被 Salamander 的人取而代之
- Known by who?   - By me, Doctor.
- 据谁了解?   - 我, 博士
Well why don't you tell the authorities,
the police or whatever?
那, 你怎么不告诉当局, 警察什么的?
Because I'm discredited, don't you see?
因为我名誉扫地了, 你没明白吗?
Because Salamander is so popular,
由于 Salamander 是如此受欢迎
and also because the man that took my place,
a man named Donald Bruce...
也因为那个顶了我位置的人, Donald Bruce...
...has since risen to become overall security chief.
...已经升到了安全总管的位置
Surely there is someone you can take your story to?
肯定你还有些人可以把故事讲给他们听?
Ah yes, Helvig believed me.
So did Assevski, and they're dead.
啊是有, Helvig 信我, Assevski 也是, 而他们都死了
However, there is one other man,
a man named Alexander Denes,
不过, 还有一个人, 名字叫做 Alexander Denes
but none of them will do anything until it's too late!
但他们没一个打算做点什么, 眼看着一切变得太迟!
I'm surprised.
我觉得奇怪
Well if Salamander is everything you say he is,
then why hasn't he tried to...
如果 Salamander 完全是你说的这种人, 那他怎么没有试图...
- Dispose of me?  - Yes
- 干掉我?   - 对
Well he has, but he's afraid.
他试过, 但他害怕
You see, the testimony of a dead man
still holds legal weight.
你知道, 一个死人的证词还是有法律效应的
Oh, I see. Well, it seems we have a problem on our hands...
哦, 我明白了. 那, 看来我们手头有一个问题是...
...whether to believe Mr Kent or not.
...要信任 Kent 先生还是不要
Well there is one way that you can find out for yourselves.
那好. 这里有一个方法, 你们可以自己弄清楚真相
Oh, how?
噢, 什么方法?
Impersonate Salamander.
假冒 Salamander
Yes I thought that's what we were leading up to.
是啊, 我估计我们就要被往这条路上引
Well I must admit, Doctor, you do look like him.
是, 我必须承认, 博士, 你真的很像他
Exactly like him.
非常像他
Yes, there's more to it than that. What about the voice?
是, 但还有别的方面, 比如说嗓音怎么办?
Well it's nearly the same pitch, only the accent.
调门差不多, 只是口音问题
Only the accent! My dear young lady.
只是口音问题! 我亲爱的年轻女士
Oh dear. Now what was it he said...
噢, 天啊. 他说了什么来着
We still cannot guarantee good summer holidays for all.
"但我们无法保障所有地方都有漂亮的夏日"
No. Guarantee... no, no, no... guaran... guarantee.
You see, it's very difficult.
不对. "保障..." 不不不, "保...保障". 你看, 这非常困难
Hmm, of course I always was interested in phonetics
嗯, 当然了我一直对发音有兴趣
Holidays... summer... summer.
＂假日...夏天..夏天＂
He must have come from Mexico,
Quintana Roo or Yucatan or somewhere...
他肯定是来自墨西哥, Quintana Roo 州或者 Yucatan 州什么的
That's incredible, Doctor, he was born at Merida,
state capital of Yucatan.
神啊, 博士. 他出生在 Merida, 是 Yucantan 州的省会
Yes, there are other very strong influences though.
是了, 但还受到了一些其它地方的强印象
Oh, I could do it in time.
But what if I did it, what then?
噢, 我可以及时搞定. 但如果我搞定了, 然后怎样?
You could walk into Salamander's research station at Kanowa,
你可以进入 Salamander 在 Kanowa 的研究站
find out how he's getting control of the separate
World Zones, and then bring out absolute proof.
发现他是如何操纵世界各区的, 把切实的证据带出来
Yes. I see.
好, 我明白了
How long did you say it would take you
to master Salamander's accent?
你说你掌握 Salamander 的口音需要多久?
I didn't. It would take three weeks, perhaps four.
我没说过. 需要三个星期, 或者四个
Well while we've been talking,
the Security Chief I told you about,
但是我们说话的这会儿, 我跟你说过的安全总管...
Donald Bruce, has since cordoned off this entire area.
...Donald Bruce, 已经封锁了这整个区域
He's coming here himself...Now!
他自己会过来... 就现在!
I'd say you've got about two minutes, Doctor.
我得说你只有大约两分钟, 博士
But that's out of the question!
但这根本不可能啊!
You know what he'll do as soon as he sees you,/?
你知道他一看见你就会做什么吗
a man who resembles Salamander so closely?
你跟 Salamander 如此之像?
- Oh that's not fair!
- Will you please listen!
- 噢, 真不公平!   - 你肯听我说一句吗!
You'll be under arrest for impersonation
as soon as he sees you. I mean it.
他一看见你, 你就会因冒充而被逮捕的. 我说真的
But isn't there another way out of this?
但就没有别的办法了吗?
Only one - be Salamander.
只有一个 - 成为 Salamander
But the clothes!
但是衣服呢!
Yes, there are some in here.
A little less eccentric, but do the best you can.
有, 这里有一些. 表现自然一点, 但要尽力而为
I won't! I can't!
我不能! 我做不到!
Your friends, Doctor, do you want them to suffer?
你的朋友们, 博士, 你想他们受罪吗?
Because they will, you know.
他们会的, 你知道
No, wait a minute! Why is a man like Bruce coming here?
不, 等一下? 为什么 Bruce 这样的人会到这里来?
Don't push me, there isn't time.
别推我, 没有时间了
You sent for him, didn't you? You tipped him off!
你叫他来的, 是不是? 你透露消息给他了!
I couldn't miss an opportunity like this,
now please come on.
我不可能错失这样的机会. 现在请快点吧
Giles, for heaven's sake, what have you done?
It's far too risky.
Giles, 老天在上, 你做什么了? 这风险太大了
Hello Kent. Doing some recruiting are you?
你好 Kent. 在招募人吗?
A bit young for killers, aren't they?
他们做杀手有点年轻了吧, 是不是?
What do you mean?
你什么意思?
All right, what do you mean by stepping in here like this?
好了, 你这样闯进来是什么意思?
Anytime, Kent. I've got the right and you know it.
Anytime I like.
随时, Kent. 我有这个权力, 你知道的. 我爱什么时候都行
All right, what do you want?
好吧, 你想要什么?
That's better, you're ex-security,
you know the way it's got to go.
这好多了. 你是前任安全官, 你知道接下来会怎样
We might as well be nice and civil about it, mightn't we?
我们还是同样会礼貌而文明的, 对吧?
That bungalow in Cedar District. In your name, right?
Cedar 区的小平房, 是你名下的, 对吧
Why?
为什么?
Do I have to tell you?
There's been an awful nasty mess out there.
非得我告诉你吗? 那里可真是血腥混乱啊
Someone has got himself shot in your living room.
有个人在你的起居室自杀了
- And who are you two?  - Jamie McCrimmon
- 你俩是谁?   - Jamie McCrimmon
- And?  - Victoria Waterfield
- 还有?   - Victoria Waterfield
- What's the matter, can't you speak?
- Don't shout at me.
- 什么情况, 你不会说话吗?   - 别朝我喊
Oh, very good, the outraged public citizen.
噢, 很好, 愤怒的公民
- Do they know who I am?
- Yes they do.
- 他们知道我是谁吗?   - 是的他们知道
A pity, I like to hear you say it.
可惜. 我想听你说一遍
Now listen to this, all of you.
现在听着, 你们所有人
One of your men was murdered in a bungalow rented to you.
有一个你的人被谋杀了, 就在租给你的房子里
The remains of two others were found
in what was left of a helicopter.
另外两个人的尸体在一辆直升机里面发现了
You were in that bungalow at the time.
当时你在那个平房里
And there were three other people with you,
two youngsters and a man. Right?
当时有三个人跟你在一起. 两个小年青和一个中年人, 对吧
Now, there was another man, wasn't there?
好, 之前还有一个人, 是不是?
So we'll deal with that first? Where is he?
所以我们先来说说那个. 他在哪儿?
Why hello Bruce, what are you doing here, huh?
哟, 你好 Bruch, 你在这里做什么, 哈?
I was under the impression
you were in the Central European Zone, Leader.
我得到的印象是, 你还在中欧区, 领袖
That's what you were meant to believe.
那正是要让你们相信的
Why?
为什么?
I do not care to be questioned by my own security!
我不喜欢被我自己的安保人员质问!
Well that's just it. How can I possibly
maintain security when you behave like this?
好我正要说这个. 你行为这样, 我怎么能保障安全呢?
I'm at least entitled to know your movements.
我至少有权知晓你的动向吧
You have a policeman's mind, Bruce.
你有一个警察的思维, Bruce
That may be! Only a few days ago you questioned me
about this man and his activities.
可能吧! 仅仅几天以前, 你还在问我这个人和他的活动情况
And we agreed that he was dangerous!
Now, I find you in his office.
而且我们都同意他很危险!  而现在, 我发现你在他的办公室
Sometimes I like to deal with matters in my own way.
有时候我喜欢用我自己的方式处理问题
- They're not holding you here?  - Holding me?
- 不是他们把你扣在这里的?   - 扣住我?
Under some threat or other.
你被威胁了什么的
No one threatens Salamander!
没人可以威胁 Salamander!
I still think I deserve an explanation, Leader.
我还是觉得我需要一个解释, 领袖
Yes, of course, you shall have it.
是的, 当然了, 你会得到的
But not now. When I return from the Central European Zone.
但不是现在. 等我从中欧区返回吧
Very well.
那好
Now what about the dead man found in your bungalow.
现在说说在你的平房里发现的死人吧
He was one of your lot, wasn't he?
他是你们当中的一个, 对吧?
Yes. Um, he was trying to protect me.
The other two wanted to kill me.
是的. 唔, 他当时在尽力保护我, 另外那两个人想杀我
Now why should they want to do that
to a nice young girl like you?
那为什么他们会对你这样一个年轻女孩儿做那种事情?
Well I...
这个我...
Obviously they thought I was there.
显然他们以为我在那里
You?
你?
Yes, Bruce, just like you,
a lot of people don't like me.
是的, Bruce, 跟你一样, 很多人不喜欢我
Don't get clever with me, Kent!
I've a good mind to...
别跟我耍聪明, Kent! 我倒相信是....
I am prepared to accept his story.
我打算接受他的故事
Well I'm not!
但我没打算!
That's interesting, but not important.
这很有意思, 但并不重要
I accept it! That's all that matters.
我接受! 这才是重要的
It's beginning to look as if these people
are working for you now. Is that right?
看起来, 这些人现在为你工作了? 是这样吗?
You still dare to question me!
They have information! I shall get it!
你还是敢质问我? 他们有情报, 我要得到!
I will see you on my return. Now leave me!
我回去之后会见你, 现在消失吧!
- McCrimmon, you said?  - Aye
- 你叫 McCrimmon, 你说过?   - 是
Well you just watch your step, that's all.
好, 你看好你的步子, 小心点
I never said a word.
我什么也没说啊
Must be the way you look, Jamie.
那肯定是你的样子看起来有问题, Jamie
You were splendid, Doctor.
你太棒了, 博士
Thank you.
谢谢你
That was a dangerous game to play.
这个游戏玩起来很危险
It paid off. All right, are you with us?
还是值得. 好了, 你加入我们吗?
I don't know where you stand, Mr Kent.
我并不知道你的立场, Kent 先生
But you and this Salamander are obviously
on opposite sides. That at least is clear.
但你和这个 Salamander 显然是对立的, 这点至少是清楚的
But which side is good? Which side is bad?
And why should I interfere?
但那一方是好的, 那一方是坏的? 为什么我要插手?
Well you're the only man who can help save the world.
不过你是唯一可以帮忙拯救世界的
But isn't that what Salamander's trying to do?
但那不是 Salamander 正在努力做的吗?
Don't you understand? Salamander...
你不明白吗?  Salamander...
Just a moment. Jamie, you're unusually quiet,
what do you think?
等一下. Jamie, 你一反常态的安静, 你怎么想的?
Well to save the world,
aye, well it sounds grand, but...
哦, 拯救世界, 是, 这听起来很伟大, 但是...
Oh, we couldn't turn our back
on a challenge like this, Doctor.
哦, 对于这样的事情, 我们不能转身而去, 博士
Well, at least I know you wouldn't.
至少, 我知道你不会的
We don't know anything about these people.
我们对这些人一点都不了解
Astrid saved our lives.
She was wounded because of it.
Astrid 救了我们的命, 她为此还受伤了
- Oh but Jamie, you don't think...
- Look, she was...
- 噢, 但是Jamie, 你不是觉得...  - 嘿, 她是...
Look, we're right about Salamander!
看, 我们对 Salamander 的看法是对的!
It won't take you long to find out for yourselves.
你们不用多久自己就能发现
How do you propose we do that?
你建议我们怎么干这事?
He'll be well guarded for a start.
首先, 他肯定被严密保护着
We can hardly steal into his study
and go through his papers.
我们很难猫进他的书房, 去查阅他的文件
That man, Bruce, said that
he was in the Central European Zone.
那个 Bruce 说过他之前在中欧区
It's a long way from Australia.
从澳洲过去路很远
It's only two hours by rocket.
坐火箭只需要两个小时
You could leave almost at once.
你们可以马上动身
- Oh, what then?  - I've had a plan ...
- 哦, 然后怎样?   - 我之前做了个计划
... for infiltrating into Salamander's
inner circle for some time.
是在某个时候渗透到 Salamander 的小圈子里去
Well I could adapt it for your two friends.
我可以按你的两个朋友修改一下
I can arrange three travel warrants and visas.
Everything you need.
我可以安排三份旅行证和签证, 所有你们需要的东西
Just three?
就三份?
Well one for Astrid, one for you and ah...
哦, Astrid 一份, 你一份, 还有...
- Victoria.  - Of course.
- Victoria.  - 当然了
Oh that's very clever of you.
How can you do that?
哦, 这很不错啊. 你怎么可以做到?
I thought you said you had no official position?
我记得你说过你已经没有了正式职位?
We have a contact there.
我们在里面有联络人
He must be a very important person.
他肯定是一个非常重要的人物
He is. Denes, Controller of the Zone.
是的. Denes, 是该区域的控制员
Oh, I see. What about me?
哦, 我明白了. 我做什么?
I think we better have a look at
Salamander's research station at Kanowa.
我想我们最好看一下 Salamander 在 Kanowa 的研究站
Yes. Ah, yes, but from a safe distance of course.
是的. 啊, 是, 但当然是在一个安全距离来看
This is dreadful news, Salamander.
I still can't believe it.
这是个可怕的消息, Salamander, 我还是不敢相信
Terrible, terrible.
可怕, 太可怕了
I don't say it will happen.
I say it can happen.
我不是说它会发生, 我是说它可能发生
Your Zone is in danger, Denes.
Here, here and here.
你的区域有危险了, Denes. 这里, 这里和这里
We've had no trouble for years in those mountains.
这些年那些山都没有出过什么事情
You don't imagine I make it up?
你不是认为这是我编造的吧?
No, no, of course not.
不, 不, 当然不是
Those volcanoes have been dead
since sixteenth century. Fedorin is right to doubt.
这些火山自从16世纪就沉寂了. Fedorin 的疑问是有理由的
A volcano is a strange thing, my friend.
I tell you the truth.
火山是一个奇怪的东西, 我的朋友. 我来跟你说说真实情况
It's like a man in the hot sun,
sleeping... still... lifeless.
就像一个在烈日下面的男人, 沉睡...沉寂...毫无生机
Then boom! He wakes full of energy!
I know volcanoes.
然后嘣! 他满能量爆发了! 我懂火山的
Isn't there a possibility of a...
miscalculation for a few degrees?
有没有可能在计算上有少许几度的偏差?
I'm never wrong.
Every one of my predictions has been accurate.
我从没出错. 我每次的预测都证明是准确的
Yes. You're record is good. I don't deny that.
是的, 你的记录保持得很好, 我不否认这个
You are too kind. Now will you listen to me!
承蒙赞许. 现在你听我的了?
Leader, the communications...
领袖, 通讯器...
I know! I know! I told you I was not to be disturbed!
我知道! 我知道! 我跟你说过我不想被打扰!
Yes, Leader.
好的, 领袖
No, wait! No, wait, Fariah, ah?
不, 等等! 不, 等等, Fariah, 哈?
- You like some refreshment, perhaps?
- Thank you.
- 你们想要放松一下吧, 怎样?   - 谢谢
No, no, not for me.
不不, 我就不用了
You're going so soon?
你这么快就要走了?
I must consult my scientific advisors.
我必须找我的科学顾问咨询一下
You still don't believe me?
你还是不相信我?
I believe you sufficiently to want to...
have your information checked.
我对你足够相信, 所以我要...核对一下你给的信息
Before I alarm my people unnecessarily.
以免我不必要地惊扰我的人民
Your scientists won't help you.
They don't know. They are amateurs.
你那些科学家帮不了你. 他们不懂, 他们太业余
No, Salamander, they are not amateurs.
不, Salamander, 他们不是业余人员
They are very clever men dedicated to their work.
他们都是非常聪明的人, 都有各自擅长的工作
But they are men, capable of human error like anybody else.
但他们是人, 就会跟其他人一样犯错
Do what you wish.
Captain!
按你的想法去做吧. 队长!
Sir!
是!
Controller Denes is leaving.
控制员 Denes 要走了
Yes, sir.
是, 长官
You will soon see that I am right.
你很快就会明白我是对的
Oh, you will stay, ah? Have a drink.
哦, 你会留下来, 哈? 喝一杯
We have a great deal to talk about, you and I.
我们有好多事情需要讨论, 你跟我
Fariah, see to him.
Fariah, 招待一下他
That might be her now. Yes.
那可能是她了. 我是
Hello, Giles? This is me, Astrid.
你好, Giles? 是我, Astrid
Right let‘s have it. What's happening?
好跟我们说说, 什么情况?
Everything's gone fine so far.
到目前一起都还好
And the rocket arrived right on time in Hungary.
而且火箭准时到达了匈牙利
And Jamie's got his entrance pass
and has started phase one.
Jamie 也拿到了他的准入证, 开始了第一阶段
- Do you think the boy can handle it?
- Well I hope so.
- 你觉得那小子能行吗?   - 嗯, 我期望如此
My goodness they're a pretty
odd lot though, aren't they?
天哪他们可是相当奇怪的一队人, 是吧?
Well actually the Doctor's with me right now.
噢, 事实上博士现在跟我在一起
Oh, I am sorry. Oh I know...
I'm sure they'll be fine.
哦, 对不起. 噢我知道了...我确信他们会没事的
What news of Denes? We must keep him posted
as to what is happening.
Denes 有什么消息? 我们必须将情况变化及时通知他
It's all right, we've contacted
and we've arranged to meet.
没事的, 我们联系过了, 并且安排了一次会面
Be careful, he's pretty well known.
小心点, 他可绝对是个公众人物
But what on earth made you
take a job as a food taster?
但到底是什么让你选了试吃食物作为工作?
She was hungry.
她那时很饿
Only thing is, now she has all the food she needs,
唯一的问题是, 现在她所需的的食物她都有了
...she has lost her appetite.
Give me a drink!
...她就没胃口了. 给我一杯喝的!
You are well protected.
你被保护得很好
Um.
唔
Very well protected.
Be calm. Sit down, drink your drink.
被保护得非常好. 冷静, 坐下, 喝你的酒吧
Ah!
啊!
Thank you for calling the guard.
I was wondering what to do about him.
谢谢你叫来了警卫. 我正不知道拿他怎么办呢
Now don't move for that box!
Not if you value your life.
现在别靠近那个盒子! 惜命的话就不要
Now all of you, back over there! That's it.
现在你们全部, 都退到那边去! 就这样
Not as well protected as you think you are, eh?
保护并不像你所以为的那么到位, 嗯?
Now when I say duck... Duck, get down!
现在等我说蹲下...蹲下, 躲避!
Look at this! What do you do boys, eh?
看看这个! 你们在做什么呢小子们, 嗯?
Read? Sleep? It's a fine thing.
看书? 睡觉? 这都还算好的
Here we have an attempt to destroy me
and where are you?
现在有人试图干掉我, 你们在哪儿?
It's not so good, boys.
It's not so good. I'm watching you.
这可不行, 小子们. 这可不行, 我盯着你们呢
Look after him. Better still, get rid of him.
照看他. 更好的是, 弄走他
- What's all this about. Eh?
- I heard two men talking.
- 这都怎么回事, 嗯?   - 我听见两个人在说话
They said they'd planted a bomb of some kind
in your radio telephone.
他们说他们在你的无线电话中植入了某种炸弹
I tried to warn them at the gates,
but they wouldn't pay any attention.
我试图在门口警告他们, 但他们没有注意到
So you break in? How you break in?
于是你闯进来了? 你怎么闯进来的?
Well I'm here on holiday with a friend.
哦, 我跟一个朋友过来度假
She's very pretty, so the guard
didn't see me slip past him.
她长得非常漂亮, 所以我溜过警卫的时候他没看见我
Why didn't you call out and warn me?
I nearly used the radio telephone several times.
为什么你不大喊几声提醒我? 我用过了无线电话好几次
Ah you'd have had me shot, most like.
啊你会枪毙了我的, 很可能
Why do you risk your skin to save me?
你为什么冒着自己生命危险救我?
Well without you
the Earth hasn't much of a chance, has it?
哦, 如果没有你地球就没有多少机会了, 对不?
You like to work for me, eh? You like that?
你想为我工作吗, 嗯? 你想不?
Oh no, you don't have to do that.
I mean, you owe me nothing.
噢不, 你不必这么做. 我的意思是, 你不欠我什么
You're quite right, boy.
你说得很对, 孩子
And I'm on holiday.
而且我还在度假
You won't find what I pay you disappointing.
你不会对我的回报失望的
Aye, there's my girlfriend too though.
啊, 但还有我的女朋友呢
Oh we might be able to find something for her.
Eh Fariah?
哦, 我们可以帮她找点什么工作. 嗯, Fariah?
Yes, your chef could use an assistant.
是的, 你的主厨需要一个助手
See to it. What do you say, eh?
你落实一下. 你怎么说, 嗯?
Well I'll give it a go.
哦, 我可以试试
But I'll say this though,
your security system's rotten.
但是我还是要说, 你的保安系统烂透了
There'll have to be changes.
必须得做出点改变了
Oh what a boy, ah?
哦, 多棒的一个小伙, 哈?
Fariah, see he gets some proper uniform
instead of this skirt.
Fariah, 给他弄套合适的制服, 换掉这个短裙
And bring him and his girlfriend to see me.
然后带他和他的女朋友来见我
Come along then.
那过来吧
What an extraordinary young man.
多个出色的一个年轻人
I prize loyalty very highly, my friend.
我非常看重忠诚度, 我的朋友
And I repay it very generously.
Like I do the girl Fariah, eh.
而且我会慷慨回报, 就像我对 Fariah 做的, 嗯?
I used to love to do this sort of thing when I was a boy.
我还是个小男孩儿时挺喜欢做这种事情
I'm sorry. It was the safest place I could think of.
很抱歉. 这是我能想到的最安全的地方
Oh, it's all right. I'm still fit enough.
哦, 没事. 我还能钻进来
Thank you for getting me the necessary documents.
谢谢你给我拿来这些必要的文件
Have you been successful?
你还顺利吗?
So far. Salamander's swallowed it.
目前还好. Salamander 已经咬钩了
I thought he would.
我料到他会的
The boy's very confident.
The girl, not so much.
那男孩儿很自信. 那个女孩儿, 就不太行
See, the point is that I'm near enough
to him to pick out something.
看, 关键是我现在离他够近, 可以挖出些什么了
This was the first time I met Salamander.
这是我第一次跟 Salamander 会面
I must say that you were right about him, Astrid.
我必须说你对他的看法是对的, Astrid
We must get rid of him. He must be stopped.
我们必须干掉他, 必须阻止他
He will be stopped!
I'm returning to Giles Kent.
他会被阻止的. 我要回到 Giles Kent 那里去了
Can you wait till we can take action?
你能坚持到我们能采取行动吗?
Oh, with a bit of luck, yes.
哦, 有点运气的话, 可以
Fedorin, would he betray you in some way?
Fedorin, 他会有可能背叛你吗?
I'm trying to think of some reason why he should.
我在尽力思考一些他那样做的理由
But these are all lies, Salamander. Lies, I assure you.
但这些都是谎言, Salamander. 是谎言, 我向你保证
So you say.
这是你的说法
What are you going to do? My family... my friends.
你打算怎么做? 我的家庭...我的朋友
My dear man. My dear Fedorin.
我亲爱的伙计, 亲爱的 Fedorin
You don't suppose I intend to
make your swindling public, eh?
你不会是认为我打算把你诈骗的事情公开吧, 嗯?
This is... this just an insurance, um.
Sit down, forget it.
这是...这只是一项保险, 唔. 坐下, 忘了它
I tell you what I'm going to do for you.
我跟你说说我打算为你做什么
What?
什么?
You are going to replace Denes
as controller of this Zone.
你将替代 Denes 成为这个区的控制员
But, don't say anything.
I'll know you'll accept.
但, 什么也不要说. 我知道你会接受的
What do you want?
你想要什么?
I'll tell you. There will be disaster in this Zone.
我会告诉你的. 这个区会有一场灾难
I cannot stop the disaster,
我无法阻止这场灾难
but I can come to the aid of this Zone
when it's happened.
但我能在它发生的时候给予这个区帮助
And take over? I see.
然后接管? 我明白了
- The Zone would be yours!
- Oh ours, Fedorin, ours.
- 这个区就是你的了!  - 噢, 我们的, Fedorin, 我们的
It's a partnership I'm offering you.
这是我提供给你的伙伴关系
Either you have half of everything, or you have nothing.
要不然你什么都有一半, 要不然你就什么也没有
But there's Alexander Denes.
但还有 Alexander Denes 呢
Oh yes, the popular, well beloved Denes.
哦, 是的, 受欢迎受爱戴的 Denes
- What a pity.  - Pity?
- 真遗憾啊  - 遗憾?
Oh didn't I tell you, Denes is going to die.
我没有告诉你吗, Denes 就要死了
Mysteriously... an assassin... terrible.
一次神秘的...刺杀...可怕啊
I can't do that! You can't ask me!
我干不了这个! 你不能让我这么干!
I think I can ask you to do anything I want.
我想我可以让你做任何事情
My predictions are accurate!
我的预测是准确的!
The entire Eperjes-Tokaj Ranges are in eruption!
整个 Eperjes-Tokaj 区域都在爆发!
Fedorin, come and look. It's very pretty.
Fedorin, 过来看看, 非常壮观
The history of Hungary is about to be rewritten!
匈牙利的历史就要被改写了
Salamander.
Salamander.﻿
What are you doing here, Bruce?
你在这里做什么, Bruce?
I had a report there was trouble here,
an attempt on your life.
我收到了报告说这里出了岔子, 有人试图要你的命
It was nothing. Come and look.
没什么大不了的. 过来看看
Terrible. Those poor people.
吓人啊, 这些可怜的人
Salamander! What have you done?
Salamander! 你干了什么?
I warned you!
我警告过你!
You couldn't have known!
You've done this somehow yourself!
你不可能知道! 肯定是你自己用什么方法干的!
The man is mad! Worse still he is incompetent!
这个人疯了! 更糟糕的是他不胜任!
I warned this man that this zone
was in danger of natural disaster...
我警告过这个人这个区有自然灾害危险...
...and he did nothing!
Issued no cautions to the public.
而他什么都没做! 连提醒都没对公众发布过
You deliberately allowed your people to suffer and die!
你故意让你的人民遭罪、死亡!
You're a traitor!
你是个卖国贼!
You're a traitor! You contrived this for your own ends.
你是个卖国贼! 你为了自己的目的制造了这场灾难
Bruce, I order you to arrest this man.
Bruce, 我命令你逮捕这个人
But this is nonsense. Fedorin, you were here.
但这是胡说. Fedorin, 你之前也在
You know this is nonsense.
你知道这是胡说
Denes you are too naive.
Denes 你太天真了
At your trial, Fedorin will be
the chief witness against you!
在你的审判会上, Fedorin 将是反对你的主要证人!
You've done very well so far, Fedorin.
到目前为止你做得非常好, Fedorin
It's nothing but a blackmail.
只是勒索而已, 没什么
Blackmail? What have I threaten you with? Nothing!
勒索? 我拿什么威胁你了? 完全没有!
No, but you would if I refused.
是没有, 但如果我拒绝的话你就会
Fedorin, I keep on telling you,
Fedorin, 我一再告诉你
this is just a form of comprehensive insurance, hm?
这只是某种形式上的综合保险, 嗯?
There's nothing for you to worry about.
你没有什么可担心的
My dear man, I've done nothing
but praise you ever since we first met.
我亲爱的伙计, 自从我们初次见面, 我对你就只有赞叹
I said you should be European Controller.
I said I would support you.
我说过你将是欧洲控制员, 我说过我会支持你
You've found out things about me,
lies that would damage me.
你发现了我一些事情, 一些会毁掉我的谎言
On the contrary, I am doing you a good turn.
恰恰相反, 我在帮你的忙
I am actually suppressing facts about you.
事实上我是在压制你那些事实
- Lies, I tell you!
- Lies... Truth... Who knows?
- 是谎言, 我跟你说!   - 谎言...真实...谁知道呢
But we wouldn't like to put them to the test, would we?
但我们并不想要拿它们来做测试, 对不?
There.
给你
What's this?
这是什么?
Used in the right way, at the right time,
it can dictate your own future
用对了方法, 用对了时间, 它就能决定你自己的未来
and the future of Alexander Denes.
还有 Alexander Denes 的未来
Poison?
毒药?
I want you to take a message...
我要你带一个消息...
- McCrimmon! What are you doing dressed like this?
- Leader's orders.
- McCrimmon! 你穿成这样是要做什么?   - 领袖的命令
Now that you're here, I've got some questions
I want to ask you.
既然你在这里, 我有些问题要问你
I have better things to do, thank you.
我有重要的事情要做, 谢谢你
I want to know what Salamander and Giles Kent
were discussing
我想要知道 Salamander 和 Giles Kent 在讨论什么
- when I saw you last time?
- It's not for me to tell you that.
- 就我上次见到你的时候 - 这个不该我来告诉你
I am concerned of Salamander's safety.
我担心 Salamander 的安全
Giles Kent is supposed to be his bitter enemy.
Giles Kent 被认定是他的死敌
If Salamander wishes you to know that,
I dare say he'll tell you himself.
如果 Salamander 想让你知道这事, 我敢说他会自己告诉你的
You'll get no confidential out of me.
你从我这里得不到机密信息
Listen. You must go away from here.
听着. 你必须离开这里
Don't get caught up in Salamander's world.
别搅和到 Salamander 的世界里面
Why? What do you mean?
You sound as if you don't like him.
为什么? 你什么意思? 听起来你好像不喜欢他
- Like him? I ...
- Oh, hello there.
- 喜欢他? 我  - 噢, 你好啊
Finish writing those menus.
把那些菜单写完
- Did you hear that?
- Aye. Work on her.
- 你听到了吗?   -  嗯, 做她的工作
I have a feeling she can tell us something about Salamander.
我感觉她能告诉我们一些 Salamander 的事情
All right. As soon as I can.
What have you been doing?
好吧, 我尽快. 你在做些什么?
I managed to slip out
and tell Astrid everything that's happened.
我找机会溜了出去, 跟 Astrid 讲了这里所发生的事情
- You might have told me, Jamie!
- There wasn't time.
- 你该告诉我的!  - 没有时间
- She's trying to get Denes away.
- And take him to the Doctor?
- 她在竭力把 Denes 弄出去  - 带他去见博士?
- He'd believe Denes.
- Aye, he would.
- 他会相信 Denes 的.   - 是, 他会的
How can she get in?
Salamander's got guards are everywhere.
那她怎么进来? 到处都 Salamander 的警卫
She's got friends here.
They're going to arrange passes...
她在这里有朋友. 他们会准备通行证...
- and the right sort of uniform.
- What sort of uniform?
- 和合适的制服  - 什么样的制服?
I don't know. Messenger delivery
or something. Ssh!
我不知道, 通讯人员什么的吧. 嘘!
Controller Denes has been arrested.
控制员 Denes 已经被捕了
I can't make up my mind whether Fedorin
is to be regarded as a new Controller or not.
我还不知道 Fedorin 是否会被公认为新的控制员
The burden of office is heavy, my friend.
I remember when I was...
公务担子很重, 我的朋友. 我记得我那时...
Alright. They've gone.
好了, 他们走了
Astrid and Giles Kent were quite right.
Salamander IS an evil man.
Astrid 和 Giles Kent 说得很对. Salamander 的确是邪恶的人
- I can somehow sense it from all the people here.
- He's bad, all right.
- 我从这里所有人那里都能感觉到  - 他是坏人, 好吧
He's had Denes arrested,
and has Fedorin eating out of his hand.
他把 Denes 抓了, 让 Fedorin 在他手里吃食
Why should he do that?
他为什么要这样做?
Remove the honest man, and put a weaker man in his place
除掉一个诚实的人, 换一个懦弱的人顶他的位子
but somehow have a hold on him,
That way Salamander can take over the territory.
然后想法抓住他的把柄, 用这个方法就可以夺走地盘了
I see - when everything's in a turmoil
because of the earthquakes.
我明白了 - 因为地震, 一切都混乱了
Aye, and that's lucky to say the least.
是, 至少可以说这还是幸运的(?)
But you don't really believe that Salamander
could cause earthquakes, do you?
但你不是真的相信 Salamander 能制造地震吧, 信吗?
I'm certain Salamander's causing the earthquakes, Doctor
我确定是 Salamander 在制造地震, 博士
and I'm sure your friends Jamie and Victoria
will tell you how bad he really is.
我肯定你的朋友 Jamie 和 Victoria 会告诉你他真的有多坏
But why make earthquakes?
但为什么制造地震呢?
Years ago, when one country wanted to invade another,
it set about attacking the confidence of that country,
以前一个国家想要入侵另外一个, 就会开始打击那个国家的自信
throwing it into confusion, making it weak.
Then it was right for take over.
让它陷入混乱, 削弱它, 然后就可以吞并了
Now, isn't that exactly what's happening here,
only in a different way?
现在这里发生的不正是这种情况吗, 只不过方法不一样罢了
What you're saying is that Salamander has found a way...
你现在说的是 Salamander 找到了一种方法...
...to harness the natural forces of the Earth.
...来利用地球的自然力量
That's a little difficult to accept.
I'm not saying it's impossible, mind you.
这有点难以让人接受. 但我不是说这是不可能的, 注意
You say it's coming from the research station.
Salamander's research station, eh?
你说它来自研究站, Salamander 的研究站, 嗯?
That's what I believe, in spite of...
Ssh! Wait a minute.
我相信是这个, 尽管...嘘! 等一下
In spite of a number of reasons,
he invented the sun-store, a brilliant advance.
尽管有其它原因, 他发明了日光存储器, 卓越的进步
He found a way of directing conserved energy
to areas starved of sun.
他找到了一个方法, 可以把存储的能量转到了日光匮乏的地区
- What made you suspicious?
- The money he was spending ast the Research Station
- 什么让你产生了怀疑?   - 他在研究站站上面花的钱
The materials involved, the food stores.
It didn't make sense.
所涉及的物料, 食物存储. 都说不通
- I had all the papers, all the requisition orders.
- But that's valuable evidence!
- 我有所有的文件, 所有的订单  - 那就是宝贵的证据啊!
All destroyed, and new ones appeared...
I was made out to be the criminal!
都被销毁了. 等新的材料出现时...我就变成了犯罪分子!
All by suggestion, of course. I was discredited.
这都是有授意的, 肯定的. 我名誉扫地了
I couldn't do it, Salamander. I couldn't do it.
我干不了, Salamander, 我干不了这事
I stood there with this man's life in my hands.
我站在那里, 手里攥着这个人的性命
This powder - I couldn't use it.
这药粉 - 我下不了手
I gave you the chance
to become something. Somebody.
我给了你机会让你成就点什么, 成为一个人物
- You failed to take it, huh
- There must be some other way.
- 但你没能接住, 哈?   - 肯定有其它的方法
Of course, my friend. Don't worry.
当然, 我的朋友. 别担心
- What?  - Don't worry.
- 什么?   - 别担心
You try, you fail - so what?
你努力了, 然后失败了 - 那又怎样?
The moon doesn't fall out of the sky!
月亮又不会跑到天外面去!
Come and sit down. Have a drink, huh?
过来坐下. 喝一小杯, 哈?
Cheer up. We'll find another way.
振作起来. 我们想别的办法
I really did try.
我真的尽力试过了
Of course you did.
当然你是
Don't worry.
别担心
Forget it, huh?
忘了它, 哈?
I have an alternative.
我有个替代方案
Your health.
为你的健康
I hope you will appreciate this wine.
It's made for me especially in Alaska.
我期望你喜欢这杯酒. 这是在阿拉斯加特意为我酿造的
One chance, my friend.
一次机会, 我的朋友
I said one chance!
我说过只有一次机会!
Some trouble in the kitchens, Leader.
厨房出了点麻烦, 领袖
The new man says he's seen
someone in the kitchen gardens.
那个新人说他在花园看见了什么人
Very well. Oh, see to that, will you?
那好. 哦, 盯着点, 行吗?
Suicide, of course. Such a pity.
自杀, 当然是. 好可惜
- I can't see anything.
- Over there by the trees!
- 我看不到任何东西  - 在那边的树丛里!
He's armed, too. Get down!
他也有枪, 趴下!
I'm going out there. Stay down here.
我去那边. 蹲在这里
When the rest of the guards come,
send them after me.
其它警卫过来后, 让他们跟我来
Yes, all right.
好, 没问题
Astrid's going to get you away.
Astrid 会把你弄走
An attempt has been made to rescue this man.
Take him out to the car.
有人试图救这个人. 带他到外面车里去
I'm sorry, Janos.
抱歉, Janos
Stop!
站住!
After them! Arrest that girl!
去追他们! 逮捕那个女孩儿!
Well, we all seem to be here,
好了, 看来我们都在这里了
except the third member of your escape committee.
除了你那逃跑小组的第三个成员
- What are you talking about?
- You were seen speaking with a girl in the park.
- 你在说什么?   - 有人看见你和一个女孩儿在园区说话
The one who tried to escape with Denes.
那个试图同 Denes 一同逃跑的女孩儿
We don't know anything about that.
We don't even know her.
我们对此毫不知情, 我们都不认识她
A diversion was caused.
There was no one outside the kitchen.
有人玩调虎离山. 厨房外面没有人
Of course there was someone, and there was shooting.
当然有人, 还有人开枪
Three shots have been fired from this gun.
It's yours, isn't it?
这把枪开过三发子弹. 这是你的, 对吧?
Pretending to save my life was ingenious,
假装救我的命, 这很高明
but ingenuity requires a constant stream of new ideas.
但高明就需要后面一系列的新点子
Yours seem to have dried up.
而你似乎已经枯竭了
I come to the Central Zone.
An attempt is made on my life.
我来到中央区, 就有人试图要我的命
Denes proves to be a traitor.
Denes 被证明是一个叛徒
Fedorin commits suicide because I uncover him.
Fedorin 自杀了, 因为我揭露了他
Do your job, Bruce.
You can see they're all in this.
干你的活吧, Bruce. 你可以看到他们都在这里面
All right. Take them away.
好吧. 把他们带走
Take your hands off me!
把你的手拿开!
Salamander, I think you should tell me what's going on.
Salamander, 我想你应该告诉我这都是怎么回事
One minute I see you with this lad McCrimmon,
前一分钟我看见你与这个 McCrimmon 在一起,
- you're working together. The next minute...
- I thought he saved my life.
- 你们一起工作, 下一分钟...  - 那是我以为他救了我的命
No, I mean before that. In Kent's office.
不, 我是说那之前, 在 Kent 的办公室
- What are you talking about?
- Well I saw you there.
- 你在说些什么?   - 但我在那里见到你了
But I haven't seen Kent in months.
但我都好几个月没有见过 Kent 了
Yes, you were with Kent, Fariah and the youngsters.
你在, 你Kent, Fariah 和这几个年轻人在一起
I thought it was so curious,
I spoke to your number two, Benik, about it.
我就觉得很奇怪, 还同你的二把手 Benik 谈过此事
- That's really the reason I came to this zone.
- But I tell you...
- 这就是我来这个区的真正原因  - 但我告诉你...
I must get back to the research centre.
You will come with me.
我必须回到研究中心去. 你得跟我来
It was you!
那就是你!
Or someone... like you?
或者, 某个...很像你的人?
Patience, Mister Kent, patience.
耐心点, Kent 先生, 耐心点
Astrid should have been in contact by now.
Astrid 应该早联系我们了
Can't you contact her?
你不能联系她吗?
If I knew where she was.
我得知道她在哪里才行
Oh no, I know she's in the Central European Zone,
哦, 不对, 我知道她在中欧区
But that's a big place.
No, we'll just have to sweat it out and wait.
但那个地方很大. 不行, 我们只能焦急地等着了
Astrid, you're back. Switch to scramble.
Astrid, 你回来了. 切到混淆模式
Scramble? Are we being monitored?
混淆模式? 我们被监视了?
- It's possible.  - Right. Switching now.
- 有可能  - 好, 现在切过去
Denes dead?
Denes 死了?
Yes, shot in the back.
是的, 后背中枪了
Well, it looks as if our friend Salamander's
had a field day, doesn't it?
那, 看来好像我们的朋友 Salamander 忙了一整天了, 是吧?
I'm afraid I haven't done very well.
恐怕我没能做得很好
Don't worry. It's not your fault.
Look, stay put and we'll join you.
别担心, 不是你的错. 这样, 安静等着, 我们来找你
The girl Astrid Ferrier,
she was in the Central European Zone.
那个女孩儿 Astrid Ferrier, 她之前在中欧区
Was she? Well she's here now. Have you found her?
是吗? 她现在在这里. 你找到她了吗?
I think so. One of my men saw someone
answering her description...
我想是. 我一个手下看到一个人跟这个描述相符...
...going into Giles Kent's office earlier.
...她走进了 Giles Kent 的办公室
Was she alone?
她一个人吗?
Yes, sir. But shortly after someone else followed her in.
是的, 长官.  但随后另外一个人跟着她进去了
Well who, man, who?
哦, 谁, 伙计, 是谁?
Leader Salamander's food taster sir, Fariah.
领袖 Salamander 的食物品尝员 Fariah
Fariah?
是 Fariah?
But what are they going to do to Jamie and Victoria?
但他们会把 Jamie 和 Victoria 怎么样?
I don't know.
我不知道
Hold them in the Central European zone
until Salamander has time to deal with them.
把他们扣押在中欧区, 等 Salamander 有时间时来处理他们
No. You're wrong. Salamander doesn't care for loose ends.
不, 你错了. Salamander 不关心这些细节(?)
He brought them back with him.
他把他们带回去了
What, to his headquarters, the Research Centre?
什么? 带回他的总部, 研究中心了?
Yes. He's going to try to get information from them.
是的, 他打算从他们那里问出点东西来
How far will he go to get it?
他为了得到信息会到什么地步?
Very far.
不择手段
Oh, that's very comforting.
哦, 那还真让人放心
I tell you I know Salamander.
我跟你说, 我了解 Salamander
Yes, I... I'm not quite clear
about your part in all this.
是的, 我...我不清楚你在这里是个什么角色?
You work for Salamander, suddenly
you fall over yourselves to betray him.
你为 Salamander 工作, 突然间你掉转身子背叛了他
I came here for that purpose, yes.
我来这里就是为了那个目的, 是的
Why?
为什么?
Because I have every reason to hate Salamander.
因为我有太多理由恨 Salamander
He blackmailed me into being his personal servant.
他要挟我做他个人的仆人
I even had to smile when he told me to.
他告诉我的时候我还不得不微笑
What sort of blackmail? What had you done?
什么样的要挟? 你做了什么?
- Does it really matter?
- Oh, no no no.
- 真的有关系吗?   - 噢, 不不不
Of course not my dear.
Well nobody's perfect, Kent.
当然没关系, 我亲爱的. 没有人是完美的, Kent
But I... I still can't help wondering why...
但我...我还是忍不住好奇为什么...
...why I hadn't tried to expose Salamander?
...为什么我没有试过揭发 Salamander?
Well you were in a unique position to do so.
对, 你位置特殊适合这么做
Because without any proof
I'd be wasting my time.
因为没有任何证据的话, 我就只会浪费自己的时间
Proof! Proof! Proof!
It always comes back to the same thing.
证据! 证据! 证据! 总是会回到同一个东西
No one has any evidence against Salamander!
没有人有 Salamander 的任何证据!
We have some.
我们有一些
Not enough! It's not enough!
Salamander covers up too well.
不够! 远不够! Salamander 伪装得太好了
I have what you want.
我有你想要的东西
But I thought that you said...
但我记得你说...
No. Not about me. Fedorin.
不. 不是我的. Fedorin
Fedorin? A public embezzler
who commits suicide?
Fedorin? 一个自杀的贪污犯?
Salamander engineered nearly every one
of those swindles, and I can prove it.
Salamander 构造了几乎每一场骗局, 我可以证明
How?
怎么证明?
Fedorin's file.
Fedorin 的文件
Is the building surrounded?
整栋楼都被包围了吗?
A three's in position, Captain.
三个方向(?)都已经就位了, 队长
Just closing up the gaps.
开始收网吧
Well you haven't brought me here
on a fool's errand, I hope?
你们带我过来不是为了耍我吧, 哈?
But I'm afraid this... this still isn't evidence,
it's... it's not real evidence.
但我担心这个...这个仍然不是证据, 它...不是真正的证据
You mean even this doesn't convince you about Salamander?
你的意思是这个仍然不能说服你对 Salamander 的看法?
Oh, I'm not saying that.
哦, 我不是这个意思
Well then you'll do it? You'll impersonate him?
怎样, 你肯干吗? 你会假冒他吗?
And of course when they see you with me
they're bound to think you're Salamander.
而且当他们看见你跟我在一起, 他们肯定会相信你就是Salamander
But I... I still don't know if I can carry it off.
但我...我还是不知道我能否瞒得过去
It's the only way to get your friends released.
这是让你的朋友得救的唯一方法
Yesss...
是的...
Of course, there are...
当然了, 有一些...
Oh I see, yes of course, there are conditions, aren't there?
哦我明白, 当然了, 有一些条件, 是吧?
You help me, I defeat Salamander?
你帮助我, 而我击垮 Salamander?
Now look, you're giving me the biggest opportunity
I'll ever have of ridding the world of this monster.
看看, 你给了我最大的机会, 让我能在这个怪物的世界里驰骋
Either I can convince you one way,
or I'll have to do it another.
要么我可以说服你, 要么我就得另外想办法
What you really want me to do is to kill him, isn't it?
你真正想让我做的, 是杀了他, 是不是?
What else do you do when someone is evil?
如果有个人很邪恶, 你还想怎么做?
Private justice, eh? Oh no, no.
私人司法, 嗯? 噢, 不, 不行
I'll expose him, ruin him, have him arrested,
我会揭发他, 毁他名声, 让他被逮捕
But I won't be his executioner.
No one has that right.
但我不会成为他的行刑者. 没人有那个权利
Sometimes it's necessary.
有时这是必须的
- No.  - Yes, Doctor yes!
- 不  - 是, 博士, 是!
Right, we'll move in.
好了, 我们进去
Either you get rid of Salamander,
要么你干掉 Salamander
or we won't lift a finger to help your friends.
要么我们一根手指也不会帮你救你的朋友
Mister Kent, look.
Kent 先生, 看
I'd make up my mind quickly if I were you.
如果我是你的话, 我会快速做出决定
- Why?  - Have a look out of the window.
- 为什么?   - 看一眼窗外面
Well, what is it?
啊, 那是什么?
What do we do now?
我们现在做什么?
Over here, quick!
在这边, 快点!
Well what's that?
噢, 那是什么?
- Through here, the ventilator shaft.
- The files.
- 走这边, 通风井  - 文件
- Come on, quick.  - But where did it go?
- 跟上, 快点  - 但它去哪儿了?
It doesn't matter, come on.
没有关系, 快点
It's locked.
被锁住了
Now you, Doctor, next.
该你了, 博士, 下一个
- Oh what about you?
- Kent! Open the door
- 哦你怎么样?   - Kent! 把门打开
Oh no, you're too important.
You go, and Giles.
噢不, 你太重要了. 你去, 还有 Giles
- I'll follow  - All right.
- 我随后  - 好吧
Very well...
很好...
...you leave me no alternative. Break it down.
...你让我没有选择了. 破开它
Get back!
退后!
Get away from that door!
离门远一点!
Did you get the others?
你找到其他人了吗?
Not yet, sir.
还没有, 长官
Now listen to me. It was you,
Astrid Ferrier, Giles Kent...
现在听我说. 这里有你, Astrid Ferrier, Giles Kent
...and another. Who was the other man?
和另外一个人. 另外那个人是谁?
You'll know soon... soon enough.
你很快就会知道...非常快
I want to know now.
我现在就想知道
Sir...
长官...
Shut up! Well?
闭嘴! 怎样?
You can't threaten me now, Benik.
现在你威胁不了我了, Benik
I can only die once,
and someone's beaten you to it.
我只会死一次, 有人已经比你抢先一步了(?)
Who was the other man?
另外那个人是谁?
Sir?
长官?
She's dead.
她死了
Good.
好
Fedorin's file. Thank you.
Fedorin 的档案, 谢谢你
What you mean is you failed.
你的意思是你失败了
I always said something should be done about Kent.
我一直都说应该对 Kent 动手
You always say. You say things, but you don't think.
你一直在说. 你是在说, 但你不思考
You exceeded your authority, Benik.
A woman's been killed.
你超出对你的授权了, Benik. 一个女人被杀了
Resisting arrest.
她拘捕
Maybe. But you can't just take the law into your own hands.
也许吧. 但你没法把法律掌握在自己手上
Giles Kent hadn't broken any rules that I know of.
Giles Kent 没有触犯任何我所知道的规则
For sure he'd show himself one day,
he was simply building up his resistance group.
他肯定会在某天露面的, 他只是在组建他的抵抗小组
Resistance group! The man's a traitor.
These people are rebels.
抵抗小组! 这人是个卖国贼, 这些人都是叛军
Bruce, you must find this man who impersonated me.
The dangers are obvious.
Bruce, 你必须找到这个冒充我的人. 危险性是显然的
He could walk in anywhere at any time
pretending to be me and ruin everything.
他可能在任何时间任何地点假冒我, 把一切都毁了
You can leave that to me.
这你就交给我吧
How so?
怎么会这样?
Benik, come with me and I'll go over
the security arrangements with you now.
Benik, 跟我来, 我现在跟你过一遍安保措施
Do as you're told!
遵守命令!
I think you'll find this interesting.
我想你会发现这个很有意思
What? The girl Fariah had this?
什么? Fariah 那个女孩儿拿到了这个?
What can I say?
我能说什么?
Yes sir?
什么事, 长官?
The records room is out of bounds.
I am not to be disturbed.
档案室现在禁止入内了. 我不想被打扰
See that the security locks are engaged.
确保安全锁已经锁上了
Very well, sir. For how long, sir?
好的, 长官. 锁多久, 长官?
For as long as I say so.
我说多久就多久
Yes sir.
好的, 长官
It seems that Salamander's
locked himself away and can't be got at.
看起来 Salamander 把他自己锁起来了, 无法联系
So?
那?
Well, suppose the place caught fire?
哦, 万一这个地方着火了呢?
It won't.
不会的
Don't be foolish!
别犯傻!
Look, I can only tell you that
when Salamander works in records,
看, 我只能告诉你, 当 Salamander 在档案室里工作时
as he does from time to time, no one is allowed in.
他经常这样的时候, 不允许任何人进去
I can understand if it were a... laboratory...
要是这是一间...实验室, 我还能理解
or... a... research room of some sort, but a...
或者...一间研究室什么的 , 但是....
a records room? What sort of records
have you got in there anyway?
一间档案室? 你们那里面有什么样的档案?
What did you want to see him about?
你想见他做什么?
Never mind. I just don't like mysteries.
没什么, 我只是不喜欢这么神秘
Salamander's far too important
to lock himself away like this,
Salamander 太重要了, 不能这样把自己锁起来
anything might happen, a world emergency.
一旦发生点什么, 都是世界级事件
Suppose I had to order you to let me in there?
如果我不得不命令你让我进去呢?
It wouldn't do any good. When the locks are switched over
they can only be opened from the inside.
那也没什么用, 一旦锁上了, 就只能从里面打开
I have returned.
Take radiation precautions.
我回来了. 你们采取预防辐射措施
I will make a report about the surface.
我要做一份关于地表的报告
He's back!
他回来了!
He's managed to get back again.
他终于又设法回来了
Let's hope he's got some good news this time.
期望这次他能带来些好消息
Do you think Salamander's found some more food, Swann?
你觉得 Salamander 找到了更多食物了没, Swann?
I hope so, otherwise we're finished.
Where's that stock list?
我期望是, 否则我们就完了. 那张储物清单呢?
Welcome back, Salamander. Are you all right?
欢迎回来, Salamander . 你没事吧?
Don't, don't come too near my friend,
I am not yet decontaminated.
别, 别靠太近, 我的朋友. 我还没消毒
I am too weary, totally weary.
我很疲惫, 完全累坏了
You shouldn't have made this trip,
Salamander, you're doing too much.
你不应该来这一趟的, Salamander. 你做得太多了
Someone has to bring back the food
for you, my friend, huh?
必须得有个人给你们带食物回来, 我的朋友, 是吧?
You know that the radiation
is slowly killing me, don't you Swann?
你知道辐射正在慢慢地杀死我, 是不, Swann?
You're just doing too much.
你付出得太多了
I worry about you all the time.
我一直都担心你们
What're you going to do when I am no longer here?
如果我不在这里了, 你们该怎么办?
Radiation gets a little more each time, hm?
辐射一次比一次强了, 嗯?
One day, that needle will stay at maximum radiation.
某一天, 那根针会一直指向最大辐射强度
- Don't say that.  - Why... Mary. Colin.
- 别那么说  - 为什么... Mary, Colin.
Huh, it's my big joke, huh?
哈, 我开的玩笑有点大, 哈?
Just to frighten you a little.
只是为了小小吓唬你们一下
I've got good news for us!
我有好消息带给大家!
We can return to the surface?
我们可以回到地面上去了?
No no no not yet, but I've found another store of food...
不不不, 还不行, 但我找到了另外一个食物储藏点...
Thank goodness!
感谢老天!
...And it is undamaged.
Colin, open the last store of wine, huh?
...而且保存完好. Colin, 打开最后那批酒吧, 哈?
Go on, you help him too, Mary.
去吧, 你也帮帮他, Mary
You must take it slowly for goodness sake.
你必须慢点, 老天
I'm all right my friend. I'm just a little dizzy. It's...
我没事, 我的朋友. 我只是有点头晕. 只是...
It's terrible up there, you know,
Swann, you've no idea.
上面情况太糟糕了, 你知道吗, Swann, 你都想不到
Right, I am ready.
好了, 我准备好了
But I still don't understand what's happened to Fariah.
但我还是没搞懂 Fariah 发生了什么
She went the wrong way. We lost her.
她走错路了, 我们弄丢她了
Well we must find her!
You don't seem to realize how vital it is.
那我们必须找到她! 你似乎没有意识到这有多关键
Doctor, hold still a moment will you?
博士, 稳住一会儿, 好吗?
Sorry.
抱歉
There. Look at that, Giles, isn't it amazing?
好了. 看一下, Giles, 是不是很惊人?
Salamander to the life.
活生生的 Salamander
Yes, it's... it's not bad.
是的, 这个...挺不赖
Shh, I think I heard something.
嘘, 我觉得我听到了什么
Perhaps it's Fariah.
有可能是 Fariah
Stay where you are. I've been looking forward
to meeting you again.
呆着别动. 我一直期待着再次见到你
Over there... No, not you.
过去那边...不, 你不去
Sit down, all of you.
坐下, 你们全部
Incredible. You fooled me the first time we met,
不可思议. 我们第一次碰面时你骗过了我...
but now, even Salamander himself
would think he was looking in a mirror.
看看现在, 就算 Salamander 他自己也会以为他在照镜子
Why? You want this man to impersonate Salamander, why?
为什么? 你想让这个人假冒 Salamander, 为什么?
How much are they paying you?
他们付给你多少钱?
I beg your pardon?
你说什么?
They want you to assassinate Salamander,
don't they? Take his place?
他们想让你刺杀 Salamander, 对吧? 取而代之?
That's ridiculous! I couldn't possibly do that.
简直荒唐! 我不可能干出这种事情
But you were preparing to impersonate him, weren't you?
但你早就在准备假冒他, 是吧?
Well well, yes.
噢好吧, 是的
Alright then, why?
那好了, 为什么?
Because Salamander holds my two friends prisoner
and I was going to attempt to rescue them.
因为 Salamander 关押了我的两个朋友, 我是打算营救他们
And at the same time get evidence
that would expose Salamander...
与此同时, 找到证据, 可以用来揭发 Salamander...
...as a traitor, blackmailer and murderer!
...证明他是个卖国贼, 勒索犯, 凶手!
Quite an ambitious plan.
How do you know such evidence exists?
计划很有野心嘛. 你怎么知道这种证据存在呢?
It exists in Salamander's records.
它存在于 Salamander 的档案室
Oh, yes, I know why you want Salamander out of the way.
哦, 是的, 我知道你为什么要除掉 Salamander
You hate him because he exposed
your profitable sideline of misusing public money.
你恨他, 因为他揭露了你那盈利颇丰的副业是挪用公款办的
Oh, it was Salamander who was misusing the money.
噢, Salamander 才是挪用公款的人
And I was dismissed from my post and
the evidence against Salamander concealed.
然后我就被从位子上赶下来, 对 Salamander 不利的证据就不见了
So you say. But you've no evidence at all
against Salamander, have you?
这是你的说法. 但你没有针对 Salamander 的任何证据, 有吗?
I tell you the evidence is in Salamander's records.
我告诉你证据就在 Salamander 的档案室
And I'm expected to take that from you?
而你就指望我信了你的邪?
We do hold evidence...
我们的确有证据...
that Salamander isn't quite
so pure and white as he's painted.
证明 Salamander 并不像他自己所粉刷的那么清白
No? What?
不清白? 什么证据?
A file, containing certain information
about a gentleman called Fedorin.
一份文件, 里面有关于一位叫 Fedorin 的先生的一些信息
Salamander was going to
use this evidence against Fedorin.
Salamander 本打算用这个证据来对付 Fedorin
Blackmail him into submission.
after he'd got rid of Denes, that is.
勒索他逼他就范 — 就在他除掉 Denes 之后
And so gain control of another zone.
这样就可以得到又一个区的控制权
Where is this file?
这份文件在哪里?
Fariah has it, Salamander's food taster.
Fariah 手上, Salamander 的食物品尝员
Fariah? But she's dead.
Fariah? 但她已经死了
Dead? But how?
死了? 怎么死的?
She was shot by one of Benik's guards, escaping arrest.
她被 Benik 的一个警卫击中了, 在逃避追捕的时候
Escaping arrest? Benik had her killed,
逃避追捕? 是 Benik 让人杀了她
because she had evidence against Salamander.
因为她有 Salamander 的证据
And Benik will return the file to Salamander.
然后 Benik 会把文件交回给 Salamander
We must get to the Research Station.
我们必须赶到研究站去
You're not going anywhere or doing anything.
你哪儿也不能去, 什么也不能做
As far as I'm concerned, this story you've told me
could be a pack of lies...
就我看来, 你告诉我的这个故事可能只是一堆谎言...
to cover your attempt to assassinate Salamander.
只为了给你企图刺杀 Salamander 找借口
Now I'm not saying I'm altogether satisfied with
Salamander or his organisation,
我现在倒不是说我全然赞同 Salamander 和他的安排
but I'll investigate in my own way.
但我会用自己的方式进行调查
Meanwhile Salamander will have found a way to cover himself,
与此同时 Salamander 会找到方法为他自己打掩护
and also a way of disposing of you.
You're digging your own grave, Bruce.
还能找到方法干掉你. 你是在自掘坟墓, Bruce
That's my affair. And I do things my own way.
那是我的事. 我做事情有我自己的方法
And I do things my way.
而我也有我的方法
Really, as Head of Security,
you should have more reliable guards.
真的, 作为安全主管, 你应该有一些更可靠的护卫
- Leader Salamander?
- Still inside, sir.
- Salamander 领袖呢?  - 还在里面, 长官
Let me know the moment the doors are opened.
门打开的时候通知我
Yes sir.
好的长官
So you've brought them?
Good. Any trouble?
看来你把他们带过来了?  很好, 遇到麻烦没?
No, a light drug saw to that.
没. 一小颗药片就搞定了
Let me know the moment they wake up.
他们醒来的时候通知我
Yes sir.
好的长官
I'm looking forward to questioning them.
I have the feeling they're going to be stubborn.
我很期待能审讯他们. 我有一种感觉他们会很顽固
So much more interesting when our prisoners are stubborn.
我们的囚犯很顽固的时候, 乐趣就多了
You're only making trouble for yourself.
Killing me won't get you anywhere.
你这只是在给自己找麻烦. 杀了我不会给你带来任何好处
We have to get to the Research Station,
and you're not going to stop us.
我们必须赶去研究站, 你不能阻止我们
But you're completely surrounded.
但你们被完全包围了
You don't really believe I came here
with just one guard, do you?
你不会真的相信我只带了一个警卫就过来了吧, 是吗?
You'd be very silly to try and fight your way out.
你要是想试着硬闯出去就太傻了
I'd give you about... thirty seconds to live if you try.
我会让你们活大约...30秒, 你们不妨一试
Alright Bruce, we might have just thirty seconds
好了 Bruce, 我们可能只有 30 秒
but you'd have exactly half that time, if you were lucky!
但你只有那一半时间, 还得运气好!
Please, Mister Kent!
You're forgetting one very important thing.
请了, Kent 先生! 你忘了一件非常重要的事情
- What?  - Me.
什么?   - 我
Without me you haven't got an earthly chance
of getting in that control centre.
没有我的话, 你进入那个控制中心的机会一丁点也没有
So?
怎样?
I told you before,
I will not have anything to do with violence!
我早跟你说过, 我不会跟暴力扯上关系!
And what about your two friends?
那你的两个朋友怎么办?
Are you going to leave them
to the tender mercies of Salamander?
你就打算让他们俩完全指望 Salamander 的仁慈?
No I am not. May I?
不, 我不会. 可以吗?
- What?  - Please? Just trust me.
- 怎么?  - 拜托? 尽管相信我
Now then, I think you agree that
at this moment your life is in my hands.
现在, 我想你会同意, 目前你的性命在我的手上
What are you doing?
你要做什么?
Hold it.
拿住它
It's alright, Mister Bruce isn't going
to shoot anyone, are you?
没事的, Bruce 先生不会朝任何人开枪的, 对吗?
Why? Why'd you do that?
为什么? 为什么你要这么做?
Because I think I know what sort of man you are
- honest and reasonable.
因为我觉得我知道你是哪种人 - 诚实而理性
Go on.
继续
I gave you back that gun because I trust you.
Now I want you to trust me.
我把枪还给你是因为我相信你. 现在我要你也相信我
You must be a complete fool, or very clever.
你肯定是个完全的傻子, 或者是极其聪明
Well I'm afraid you will have to
make up your mind to that right away.
那, 恐怕你必须得立刻打定主意
What do you hope to gain from this gesture?
你摆这个姿态是期望获得什么?
Your confidence.
你的信心
Do you believe Kent's accusations against Salamander?
你相信 Kent 对 Salamander 的控诉吗?
I think there's reasonable doubt about
Salamander's personal integrity,
我觉得 Salamander 正直与否是存在一定程度的疑问的
but there's only one way to get proof.
但只有一个办法获得证据
By getting into Salamander's Research Station?
得先闯入 Salamander 的研究站?
Yes. And my two young friends may have some information.
是的. 而且我的两个年轻朋友也可能有些信息
And if there isn't any evidence?
但如果没有任何证据呢?
Then you'll be perfectly free to arrest us
and put us in prison, won't you?
那你就完全可以逮捕我们, 把我们扔进监狱, 行吗?
Alright, I'll do it, on one condition.
好吧, 我干了. 但有一个条件
And what's that?
什么条件?
That you and I go alone,
Kent and the girl stay here as hostages.
就是你和我单独去, 而 Kent 和这个女孩在这里做人质
No wait a minute, I must go with him.
不, 等一下, 我必须跟他一起去
No, Kent, you stay here.
I must be mad to trust you.
不, Kent, 你必须呆在这里. 我要是相信你就是疯了
I only hope your impersonation of Salamander fools Benik.
我只是期望你假冒的 Salamander 能骗过 Benik
If it doesn't, we're in dead trouble.
如果没有, 咱俩都麻烦大了
Here, take this. Keep those two in the caravan.
来, 拿着这个. 让他俩呆在车里
Oh, and, um, watch the girl. Come on.
噢, 对了, 看好这个女孩儿. 来吧
Ah, how we getting on here, huh?
Ah, all this? That's a good haul.
啊, 我们进展如何, 哈? 这些都是? 收获不少嘛
Stand by to make your report, Swann.
准备开始做你的报告, Swaan
Reaching full power here, Swann.
这里已经达到最大功率, Swaan
Salamander, I must see you.
Salamander, 我必须见你
Not now, we are too busy.
现在不行, 我们太忙了
This is urgent.
这事很紧急
Oh very well.
噢, 好吧
Now what's the matter, huh?
现在说说, 什么事, 哈?
What's this? What is this?
这是什么? 这是什么?
What?
什么?
Newspaper. It's a piece of newspaper.
报纸. 这是一张报纸
So?
怎么?
Well go on, look at it. Read it. Last year's date.
继续, 看一眼眼, 读一下. 日期是去年
Look at the bit of headline there. THERE!
看看那里的头条, 那里!
Control yourself, Swann. You'll go mad.
控制一下自己, Swann, 你这是要疯了
"Holiday Liner Sinks"!
"假日航线沉没＂!
You say there's a global war. Radiation everywhere.
你说有一场全球战争, 到处都是辐射
How can there be holiday liners? Tell me how!
怎么会有假日航线呢? 告诉我怎么会!
You've lied to us, haven't you? HAVEN'T YOU?
你对我们撒谎了, 有没有? 有没有?
In a way, Swann, yes. I had to.
某种程度上, Swann, 算是吧. 我迫不得已
Had to? What do you mean had to?
不得已? 你什么意思, 不得已?
Well it's true that... that the war is over,
嗯, 的确是...战争已经结束了
but have you any idea what happens to people
who've been involved in a nuclear war? HAVE YOU?
但卷入核战争的人会怎样你有概念吗? 有吗?
Course I haven't, I've been down here.
我当然没有, 我都在这下面
Those who are lucky enough to escape the annihilation
have their bodies eaten away by radiation poisoning.
那些侥幸捡了一命的人, 身体却难逃辐射的毒害
They're deformed in mind and body.
他们在精神和身体上都是畸形
But this, this, this newspaper?
但这个, 这个, 这份报纸呢?
They have a kind of society,
but it's... it's evil! Corrupt!
他们有着某种社会, 但它是...它是邪恶的! 堕落的!
You don't think I could expose you to that sort of thing?
你不会认为我会让你们去接触那种东西吧?
Think of Mary and the other women.
想想 Mary 和其他女人
You could have told me, at least.
你本可以告诉我的, 至少
I decided not to.
我决定了不告诉
You should have told me.
你应该告诉我的
I thought it was best.
我想那是最好的
And what about the natural disasters
we've been organising?
那我们一直在制造的自然灾害是怎么回事?
The volcanoes, earthquakes?
那些火山, 地震?
Swann, they're not fit to live.
Swann, 它们不适合居住
You're murdering them, killing them off!
你在谋杀他们, 残害生命!
I want you and the others
to inherit the Earth, make a new world.
我想让你和其他人继承地球, 创造一个新世界
Yes, I know all about that,
but not at the price of wholesale murder!
是的, 这我都知道, 但不是以大批谋杀为代价!
It's not murder! If you could see
you would understand. It's an act of mercy.
这不是谋杀! 如果你见了你就会明白, 这是仁慈之举
There must be some other way.
肯定有其它的办法的
NO!
没有!
I won't take your word any more.
I want to see for myself.
我不再相信你的话了, 我要自己去看
You, you, you'd be horrified.
你, 你, 你会吓坏的
Maybe.
可能
The radiation would kill you!
辐射会杀死你
I'll chance that.
我会赌一把
Very well. But, but promise me one thing,
you won't tell the others.
好吧. 但是, 答应我一件事, 你不会告诉其他人
Why shouldn't I?
为什么我不会?
Because I am right and you are wrong!
因为我是对的, 你是错的!
You, you wouldn't want to,
you wouldn't want to hurt them like that, huh?
你, 你不会愿意, 你不会愿意伤害他们那样的人的, 哈?
And if you're lying,
and I want to tell when I get back...?
但如果你是在撒谎, 等我回来我就会告诉他们...
How can I stop you?
我怎么能阻止你呢?
You'd better, ah, tell them you're coming with me.
你最好...告诉他们你要跟我一起去
Say er, say you've persuaded me.
就说, 呃, 说你说服了我
Swann, trust me, don't go ahead with this huh?
Swann, 相信我, 别继续这事, 嗯?
I have to.
我必须去
Where are we?
我们在哪儿?
You're in the Australasian zone.
I had you brought here especially.
你在澳洲区, 我特意让人带你们过来的
Why?
为什么?
So that Salamander could ask you some questions.
以便 Salamander 可以问你一些问题
For all the answers he's gonna get
he might as well have left us there.
就为了得到那些答案的话, 他也可以把我们留在那里
Stand up when you talk to me!
跟我说话的时候站起来!
You'll get nowhere by shouting.
你大声嚷嚷也得不到什么
On the contrary. I'm going to get everything
I want from you two.
恰恰相反, 我会从你俩这里得到一切
We'll not tell you a thing.
我们不会告诉你任何事情
That's good. I like that.
这样很好, 我喜欢这样
- What?  - Spirit. Resistance.
- 什么?   - 斗志, 顽强
You've got plenty of both, haven't you, boy?
这两样你都很充足, 是吗, 小子?
Well I wonder how long you'll last.
Five minutes?
我好奇你能撑多久? 5分钟?
No, a little longer, maybe? Ten, perhaps?
不, 会长点儿, 可能不? 10分钟, 也许?
- What do you mean?
- Come now, you don't think...
- 你什么意思?  - 得了, 你不会认为...
...I'm just going to sit here
and ask questions, do you?
...我会干坐在这里问你问题吧, 是吗?
You must have been a nasty little boy.
你以前一定是一个令人讨厌的小男孩儿
Oh I was. But I had a very enjoyable childhood.
哦, 我是. 但我有一个相当愉悦的童年
Ha ha hah. Yes, I thought so.
Spirit, plenty of spirit.
哈哈哈, 是的, 我猜也是. 斗志, 昂扬的斗志
Oh, we're going to enjoy ourselves, aren't we? Now then...
哦, 我们会一起享受的, 对不? 现在...
I... I thought you were going to take us to see Salamander?
我...我记得你是打算带我们去见 Salamander 吧?
Yes I will. But he'd expect me to do my little best first.
是, 我会的. 但他期望我先尽我自己努力
You lay a finger on her, I'll kill you.
你动她一根手指头, 我就会宰了你
Will you? How? Ha ha ha.
你会吗? 怎么宰? 哈哈哈
No. I think the time's come for you
to answer my questions, don't you?
不, 我觉得现在轮到你来回答我的问题了, 对不?
Come here, girl!
过来, 女孩儿!
If you don't, I shall have to shoot one of you.
如果你不过来, 我就会朝你们其中一个开枪了
Oh, not a mortal wound. In the leg, perhaps?
哦, 不是马上会死的那种. 射在腿上, 也许是?
Better go. Don't worry.
赶紧走, 别担心
There. That's better.
对啦, 这好多了
Oh, such pretty hair, don't you think?
哦, 多漂亮的头发啊, 你不觉得吗?
Alright, leave her alone. What do want to know?
好吧, 放开她. 你想知道什么?
Quite a lot. And you're going to
tell me everything. Aren't you?
很多. 你会告诉我所有事情吧, 会吗?
- Aaah!  - All right, yes!
- 啊!  - 好了, 行!
Who's behind you? Is it Giles Kent?
你们后面是谁? 是 Giles Kent 吗?
Oh, so they're here, eh?
哦, 那他们在这里了, 嗯?
Salamander, I, I thought you were in Records?
Salamander, 我..我记得你还在档案室?
Have they told you anything yet?
他们告诉你什么没有?
Not yet.
还没有
Very well. Bruce and I will take over.
很好, Burce 和我接手吧
You may go, and er,
take your little puppy dog with you, hm?
你可以走了, 呃, 带走你的小狗行吗, 嗯?
Now...
现在...
We can't tell you anything.
我们告诉不了你什么
Of course not. We know everything.
当然不能. 我们知道所有事情
We know about Giles Kent,
我们知道 Giles Kent 的事
we know about the girl called Astrid,
我们知道那个叫 Astrid 的女孩儿的事
and we know about your friend the Doctor.
我们还知道你们的朋友 - 博士的事
I don't believe you.
我不相信
A childish plan to impersonate me.
Yes the truth, isn't it?
冒充我是个幼稚的计划. 这是实话吧, 对不?
Ah but he didn't agree to it.
是, 但他没有同意
But you two were sent to
the Central European zone to stir up trouble.
但你俩被派往了中欧区, 想把水搅浑
If you want to know the truth,
如果你们要知道实情
Giles Kent told us a story and we weren't sure.
Giles Kent 跟我们说了一个故事, 但我们并不确定
Before the Doctor could do anything
在博士采取任何行动之前
we had to come here
and find out what person you were like.
我们必须到这里来, 弄明白你是什么样的人
Yeah, and we found that out right enough.
是, 而且我们发现的情况够多的
You see Bruce, they just terrorists.
Not very big fry, either.
你看 Bruce, 他们只是恐怖分子. 不是什么大鱼
All this nonsense about proof against me.
一直叨叨着所谓针对我的证据
If you're doing so much good for the world,
why are you so afraid for your own life?
如果你为世界做了如此多的贡献, 你为什么会如此担心你自己的性命?
Aye, and why do you have so many enemies?
是. 而你为什么有这么多的敌人?
- Personal guards?
- Your own food taster?
- 私人保镖?   - 你自己的食物品尝员?
And why destroy the one man
people trusted, Alexander Denes?
为什么还毁掉一个人们信任的人, Alexander Denes?
- Aye.  - What do you mean, destroy?
- 是  - 你什么意思, ＂毁掉＂?
One of your men shot him.
你一个手下枪杀了他
Trying to escape?
他试图逃走?
He shot him deliberately.
他蓄意开枪的
Aye. And that girl Fariah,
well she was close to Salamander,
是. 还有 Fariah 那个女孩儿, 她与 Salamander 关系如此之近
she'd speak against him, I know she would.
还是会出言反对他, 我知道她会的
Fariah is dead.
Fariah 已经死了
Dead?
死了?
You've had her murdered too, have you?
你把她也谋杀了, 是吗?
- Why you...
- Oh, Victoria! Don't hit me!
- 为什么你...  - 哦, Victoria! 别打我!
You wouldn't hit your old friend the Doctor, would you?
你不会打你的老朋友博士的, 是吧?
I wouldn't leave you in the tender mercy of Salamander.
我不会把你们扔下, 任凭 Salamander 乱来的
You're the Doctor?
你是博士?
You don't believe me? Oh. Huh.
你不相信我? 噢, 哈
Only, you made me leave it in the TARDIS.
只是, 你让我把它留在 TARDIS 里面了
- It is him!  - Oh, Doctor!
- 真是他!  - 哦, 博士!
"Tardis"? "Tardis", what's that?
"TARDIS"? "TARDIS" 是什么?
Well, it's a little place that we three have in common.
哦, 只是我们三人共同熟悉的一个小地方
You must admit they thought
I was Salamander to begin with.
你必须承认他们一开始把我认做了 Salamander
Yes. I concede that. But there's still no proof.
是的, 我承认. 但还是没有见到证据
No, but there's enough doubt in your mind...
没有, 但你脑袋里面已经有了足够的疑问了吧
to make you go on asking questions, isn't there?
That's why we came here.
你想问很多问题, 是不? 这就是为什么我们来这里
Wait. What happens up there?
等等. 上面什么情况?
Oh, it ends in a ruined building.
This is where I bring the stores,
噢, 前面倒塌的建筑, 没路了. 这是我带储备来的地方
- uh, you would be safer here.
- Safer?
- 你在这里会安全些  - 安全些?
Yes, the radiation.
I don't think it filters down here.
是的, 因为辐射. 我觉得还没有渗透到这里来
I still want to see the surface.
我还是想去看看地表
You will, you will.
你会看到的, 你会的
I should have insisted on going with him.
Bruce should have taken me.
我应该坚持跟他一起去的. Bruce 应该带上我
You know he doesn't trust you.
你知道他并不信任你
He wouldn't trust his own grandmother.
他连他自己的祖母都不信任
Oh, never mind, Giles. We've come a long way.
噢, 别管了, Giles. 我们走了好远了
Months ago, well a few weeks ago even,
nobody would have even listened to you.
几个月以前, 噢甚至几个星期以前, 没人肯听你的
Oh, maybe.
噢, 也许吧
There's no maybe about it.
这并不是什么也许
Yeah perhaps you're right.
Bruce listens to us at last.
是, 也许你是对的. Bruce 最终肯听我们说了
He's even prepared to ask questions, that's fine, but...
他甚至打算问问题了, 这很好, 但是...
I know Salamander.
He'd talk his way out of the quicksand.
我了解 Salamander. 他陷进流沙都能靠一张嘴出来
Well what else can we do,
the guard's still outside?
那我们还能做什么, 警卫都还在外面?
I must get into the Research Centre.
我必须进入研究中心
I've got to make sure that Bruce
understands the evidence, understands it, Astrid.
我得确保 Bruce 能理解这个证据, 理解它, Astrid
Don't you realize, he mightn't know
what he's looking for. I know.
你没有意识到吗, 他可能不知道他要找什么. 而我知道
But we can't attack the guard.
It would only make matters worse.
但我们不能袭击警卫. 这只会让事情变得更糟
Not if I was to give Bruce real evidence.
不会, 我会给 Bruce 真正的证据
Giles, how long would it take you
to get to the Research Station?
Giles, 你赶去研究站要多久?
Well just a few minutes, I've got a pass.
It's just a matter of getting there.
噢, 只要几分钟. 我有通行证, 只是赶到那里的问题
Alright, I think I can help you.
好了, 我想我可以帮你
I'll draw the guard off and leave you alone.
我去把警卫引开, 单独留你在这里
You think you can do it?
你觉得你可以做到?
Yes, I think so.
是的, 我觉得可以
But I thought you said we weren't going to attack the guard?
但我记得你说过我们不打算袭击警卫?
Oh, we're not going to attack the guard,
噢, 我们不会去袭击警卫
but there is going to be an attack. A fatal one.
但还是会有一次袭击, 致命的一次
Where does this lead?
那通向哪里?
It goes on up and comes out in a field.
它往上走, 出口在一片空地上
What about radiation?
辐射怎样?
Here it's almost negligible.
这个地方基本可以忽略
You mean you could have brought others here from below?
你是说你可以把其他人从下面带到这里来?
I don't understand you.
我搞不懂你
Don't you realise what a break
it would be for them,
难道你没意识到, 这将对他们来说是个多大的突破?
just moving away from that underground tomb once in a while?
只要隔一段时间能够从那个地下坟墓逃离一下?
You seem to forget, Swann,
I've brought people up here before!
你似乎忘了, Swaan, 我之前带人上来过!
There's always an element of risk!
总是会有某种危险存在的!
I still want to have a look at these people
you say are living on the surface.
我还是想看一眼你说的那些住在地表的人
Where does that lead?
那边通向哪里?
Oh, that's a dead end.
It's a place I sometimes rest.
哦, 那是条死路. 我有时候在那里休息
It's very hard work, you know, bringing all the...
真的很辛苦的, 知道吗, 带着所有这些...
Yes, I know that.
This way, then?
是的, 我知道这个. 那边呢?
You, you sure you... won't change your mind, huh?
你, 你确定...不改变主意了, 哈?
What's going on here?
这里什么情况?
He's been shot. Through the window.
他中枪了. 从窗外射进来的
Alright, stand back.
好吧, 往后站
He's finished.
他完蛋了
Better get a doctor anyway, just in case.
最好还是找个医生, 以防万一
Hey! Come back!
嘿! 回来!
Hellllp! Somebody help me.
救命! 谁来救救我
Heeellllp! Help... Somebody help me...
救-命-! 救命...谁来救救我!
Who did this to you?
谁把你这样了?
A man named... Salamander.
一个叫做...Salamander 的人
Salamander?
Salamander?﻿
He did it... down there...
他干的...在那下面...
This is Salamander.
我是 Salamander
I want a security escort to come
to the interrogation room immediately.
我要一个护卫小队立刻到审讯室来
I'm releasing two prisoners.
They are to be conducted to the main gates and set free.
我要释放两个囚犯. 要把他们带到大门, 然后释放
Is that understood? Good.
明白了吗? 好
- Well I hope that works.
- So do I.
- 好了我期望这能行  - 我也期望
What do you want us to do when we get outside?
等我们出去了, 你想让我们做什么?
There are plenty of public phones in the area.
在这个地区有很多公共电话
Dial double zero one and ask for a man named Forrester.
拨001, 找一个叫做 Forrester 的人
- Eh?  - He's my deputy to this area.
- 嗯?  - 他是我在这个区域的副官
Double zero one Forrester.
拨001找 Forrester
Tell him where I am and just say "redhead".
告诉他我在哪里, 只需要说＂红头＂
Redhead.
"红头"
Redhead. Is that clear?
"红头＂, 明白了吗?
Redhead? Is that your wife?
＂红头＂, 是你妻子吗?
It's our emergency call.
这是我们的紧急联络语
Sorry.
抱歉
Salamander... Is the, is the pass in order?
Salamander ...那个, 那个通行证有效吗?
Very well, you have my authority.
很好, 我给予授权
What's all that about?
这都是什么情况?
We have a visitor.
我们有客人来访了
Giles Kent. What are you doing here?
Giles Kent, 你在这里做什么?
Oh, I've been looking forward to this meeting.
哦, 我一直期待着这次会面
You're getting careless.
You didn't double lock the doors.
你大意了, 没有给门上双重锁
Oh, its all right, I've done it now.
哦, 没事的. 我现在已经锁上了
The only way anybody can get through there
is to blast their way through.
谁想穿过它, 唯一的方法是炸开一条路
- How did you get into the Research Centre?
- Oh, you know me.
- 你怎么进入研究中心的?   - 噢, 你知道我的
There isn't a pass in the world
I can't get my hands on, if I put my mind to it.
这个世界上没有哪个通行证我搞不到手, 只要我想要
You won't find it so easy getting out.
你会发现想出去就没那么容易了
Really? Well we'll see.
真的吗? 那我们回头看看
I'm not on my own this time.
I've got friends here with me.
我这次不是单独来的, 带了朋友来这里
And between us we're going to fix you once and for all.
而咱们俩这次就一劳永逸地解决你
You always were a tiresome man, Kent.
你一直都是一个令人讨厌的家伙, Kent
I'm going to be more than tiresome this time.
我这次打算比＂令人讨厌＂还要过分
You know the biggest mistake you ever made...
你知道你犯下的最大的错误...
was not killing me when you had the chance.
就是你有机会的时候没有杀死我
Oh so you going to kill me huh? How petty.
哦, 看来你打算杀死我, 哈? 很好
What good do you think that will do?
你觉得这会带来什么好处?
Hold it! Now don't move quickly,
别动! 现在不要做大动作
my nerves are a bit shaky at the moment.
我的神经这会儿可有点不稳
We must get in there somehow.
我们必须想法进去
We can't without the emergency key,
and Salamander has it in there.
没有紧急钥匙我们也没办法, Salamander 拿进去了
- We could burn our way in.  - Never.
- 我们可以把门溶掉闯进去  - 别想
- Why not?
- It's an X-structure alloy, you'd hardly scratch the surface.
- 为什么不能?  - 这是X结构合金, 你连表面都刮花不了
We'll have to try it. Get the gear up here. Fast!
我们必须得试试. 把装备拿过来. 快!
Ha ha ha. Never get away with it?
Oh, that's good, coming from you.
哈哈哈. 永远甩不掉? 噢, 这太好了, 你也有这时候(?)
Don't you realize you're dispensable,
你没意识到你是可有可无的吗?
and the world is going to get along fine
without you from now on.
而且从今往后这个世界没有你也能运转得很好了
The only good idea you ever had in your life
was getting rid of me...
你这一辈子唯一有过的好点子就是干掉我
and you couldn't even do that properly, could you?
而你都不能好好落实, 能吗?
Ha ha ha. And now I'm back and you're finished.
哈哈哈, 现在我回来了, 而你完蛋了
Oh, what's that?
噢, 那是什么?
They're breaking down the door.
他们想把门破开
They don't appear to be having much success.
他们似乎没有什么进展
It's not cutting, sir.
切割不了, 长官
Never mind, keep at it.
别管, 继续
You're trapped, aren't you?
你被困住了, 对吧?
You're a fool, Salamander.
You don't think I'd forgotten already, do you?
你真傻, Salamander. 你不会以为我已经忘记了吧, 是吗?
What?
什么?
I've been with you too many times in this room in the past,
以前我跟你在这个房间太多次了
not to know where this leads to.
不可能不知道这个东西通向哪里
Your little bolt-hole.
你的小小藏匿之地
Halfway down the tunnel.
A passage out to the fields...
在隧道的中途, 有一条通道通向空地
and enough explosives down there
to stop you or your thugs following me.
那里有足够的炸药, 用来阻止你那些跟在我后面的家伙
Well that's very interesting Mister Kent.
Why didn't you tell me that before?
啊, 这很有意思 Kent 先生. 你之前为什么不告诉我?
- Oh no, it can't be.  - Oh, I'm afraid it is.
- 噢, 不, 不可能  - 噢, 恐怕可能
Oh look. Here's another surprise for you. Look behind you.
噢, 看, 这里还有一个给你的惊喜, 看你后面
Astrid, you've come just in time.
Astrid, 你来的正是时候
It's too late, Giles, I know everything.
太迟了, Giles, 一切我都知道了
That's him, that's the man
who took us down there in the first place.
就是他, 一开始就是他把我们带去地底下的
Giles Kent, we thought you were dead.
Giles Kent, 我们以为你已经死了
Now look, I've never seen these people before in my life.
都听着, 我一辈子都从来没见过这些人
They told me everything.
You and Salamander were in it together...
他们把一切都告诉我了. 你和 Salamander 之前都在里面...
...You built an atomic shelter,
took some people down for an endurance test.
你们建了一个原子弹掩体, 带了一些人下去做耐力测试
The next person they saw was Salamander...
他们看见的第二个人就是 Salamander...
...who told them that an atomic war had started.
...后者告诉他们核战争开始了
You see, Kent...
你看, Kent...
Oh, be careful, Doctor. He'll kill you.
噢, 小心点, 博士. 他会杀死你的
You kept us down like animals.
你把我们像动物一样关在下面
Why? Why did you do it to us?
为什么? 为什么要对我们这样?
We had to have someone create
the natural disasters, didn't we,
我们必须得有人来制造自然灾害, 对不
and we fooled you all!
而我们骗过了你们全部!
You didn't fool me, Kent...
你没有骗过我我, Kent...
You didn't suspect me.
你没有怀疑过我
Any man who resorts to murder as eagerly
and as rapidly as you must be suspect.
任何一个像你这般如此急切地诉诸于谋杀手段的人, 必须怀疑
You didn't just want to expose Salamander,
you wanted to kill him and take his place.
你不只是想揭发 Salamander, 你想要杀死他并取而代之
And I will! Think you're going to stop me?
And these people?
我会的! 觉得你们能阻止我? 就这些人?
Now move out of the way, quick!
We'll see who'll stop me!
现在都散开, 快! 我们看看谁能阻止我!
Stop him, Stop him!
He's going to try and blow the place up!
拦住他, 拦住他! 他要炸了这个地方!
Come on then!
快点啊!
No! Don't touch that door, it's red hot.
不! 别碰那个门, 都烧红了
What do you mean?
你什么意思?
Well it's locked.
They're trying to burn through from the other side.
噢它被锁住了. 他们想把它从另外那边烧穿
Still no good, sir.
还是不行, 长官
Look! Salamander!
看! Salamander!
Yes. I wonder if he knows Kent's on his way?
是的. 我在想他是否知道 Kent 在来的路上
You always were a fool, weren't you?
你一直都是一个傻子, 对吧?
Now wait a minute.
They'll be after both of us now.
现在等一下, 我们俩现在都会被他们追
Oh no they won't.
噢, 不, 他们不会的
I tell you, they know!
我告诉你, 他们知道!
So what you want me to do, huh?
Bury our differences, hmm?
所以你想让我做什么, 哈? 放下我们的分歧, 嗯?
I didn't need you once, I still don't need you.
我以前不需要你, 现在还是不需要你
Now wait a minute.
The place is mined, we know that.
现在等等, 这个地方有地雷, 我们知道的
We planned it for years, together.
我们计划了好些年, 一起干的
Between us we can destroy them all, and the evidence.
我们一起可以消灭他们, 消灭证据
Just you and me, Salamander.
就你和我, Salamander
You and me? What use are you to me?
你和我? 你对我有什么用?
You were useful once, but now...
你以前挺有用, 但现在...
No. No...
不, 不...
Ha ha ha ha. You won't get away
from me, Kent. Ha ha ha ha.
哈哈哈哈, 你甩不掉我的, Kent. 哈哈哈哈
Ha ha hah. I told you you could not escape me.
哈哈哈, 我告诉过你你逃不出我手心
Well if I'm going to die, Salamander,
you'll die with me.
好, 如果我要死, Salamander. 你也得跟我一起死
No! No!
不! 不!
Aaaaaaa!
啊!
Come on Doctor,
we're going to get you out of here.
快点博士, 我们带你离开这里
Oh, look, Salamander, Giles, they're dead.
噢, 快看, Salamander, Giles, 他们都死了
We'll be dead too if we don't get out of here.
如果我们不离开这里我们也会死的
The people...
那些人...
People. What people?
人? 什么人?
The people underground in the deep shelter.
在地底掩体里面那些人
They may have been killed.
他们可能已经死了
I promised Swann I'd get them out.
我答应了 Swann 我会去把他们带出来的
But that's not your fault.
You couldn't have done more.
但这不是你的错, 你已经做得够多了
There's a TV monitor screen in there.
There must be a link to the deep shelter.
这里面有个监视器, 那里肯定可以连通地底掩体
It's alright! They're alive!
没事了, 他们都活着!
How are you going to get to them?
你打算怎么去救他们呢?
There's a tunnel from outside.
We can get to it outside the Research Station.
外面有一条隧道. 我们可以从研究站外面过去
But that's probably been destroyed by the explosion.
但它很可能被爆炸摧毁了
We'll get to them somehow.
不管怎样我们得去找他们
Lookout!
小心!
Get me some men. I'll lead them.
给我一些人, 我来带领他们
Alright. I'll go with you.
好吧, 我也跟你去
Oh good then. That's splendid. I'll come too.
哦, 那太好了. 非常棒. 我也去
Oh no Doctor. It's far too dangerous.
They might mistake you as Salamander.
噢, 不行博士, 太危险了. 他们可能把你当作 Salamander
Oh yes. Ooooh.
噢是的, 噢
- Are you hurt?  - Oh I'm alright.
- 你受伤了?   - 哦我没事
I'll come with you as far as the gates.
Come along, we must go.
我陪你走到门口吧. 都过来, 我们得走了
I thought you were never coming.
我以为你再也不会来了
Hey Doctor, are you alright?
嘿, 博士, 你没事吧?
Oh there you are Doctor.
You do look in a state. Come and sit down.
哦, 你到了啊博士. 你脸色太差了, 过来坐下
I told you it wouldn't be long.
You, you worry too much.
我告诉过你不会太久了. 你多虑了
We shouldn't have left him.
我们不应该离开他的
You see, after the explosion, Doctor,
we dinna know what to do.
你看, 博士, 爆炸之后, 我们都不知道该怎么办了
You said to come back here, which we did,
but I'm sure we were followed.
你说过要回这里来, 我们照做了, 但我不确定我们是否被跟踪了
Please, can we start straight away?
摆脱, 我们能直接开始了不?
Me, Doctor? But you said we were never to touch the controls.
我吗, 博士? 但你说过我们永远不要碰那些开关
Quite right, Jamie. Welcome to the TARDIS.
没事的, Jamie. 欢迎来到 TARDIS
Thank you. You're doing so well impersonating me, ah,
谢谢你, 你在冒充我这方面做的很好
I thought I might return the compliment.
我觉得我应该回报一下
And Giles Kent?
Giles Kent 呢?
Unfortunately, didn't survive the explosion.
很不幸, 没能在爆炸中幸存下来
We're going to put you outside, Salamander,
我们打算放你出去, Salamander
no friends, no safety, nothing.
没有朋友, 没有安全, 什么都没有
You'll run, but they'll catch up with you.
你可以跑, 但他们会追上你的
No!
不!
And now I'm going to kill you.
而现在我要杀了你
No you don't.
不, 你不能
Oh, Doctor!
噢, 博士!
Victoria! Jamie! Hold onto something!
Victoria! Jamie! 抓牢什么东西!
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaa!
啊----!
Jamie! Oh!
Jamie! 噢!
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaa!
啊----!